Guide to the Vicki Hearne Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Papers, 1920-2001; Series IV; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  - Spiral notebooks
    - Spiral-bound notebook containing draft of job resume, job application letter, draft of letter to "John," and miscellaneous writings, undated (Box 38, Folder 499)
    - Notes made during Hearne's illness, 2001 (Box 38, Folder 500)
    - Delaudid doses, [2001] (Box 38, Folder 501)
  - Art work
    - Cartoon drawing, undated (Box 38, Folder 502)
    - Sketchbooks, undated (Box 38, Folder 503-504)
    - Drawings by Katrin Wiese, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 505-506)
    - Posters advertising Hearne readings, 1987, undated (Box 39, Folder 507)
    - Ephemera, 1981-2001 (Box 39, Folder 508)
    - Newspaper and magazine articles about Hearne, 1984-2001 (Box 39, Folder 509)
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1920, 1977-1996, undated (Box 39, Folder 510-512)
- Photographs and Audiotapes, 1955-1992; Series V; 0.42; (2 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by subject within each format category.
  This series contains photographs of Hearne, family and friends, and dogs and horses, and date from 1955 to 1992. Additional photographs may be found as enclosures with correspondence in Series I, and with publicity material for Bandit in Series II. The series also contains two audiotapes.
  - Photographs
    - Hearne, 1955 (Box 40, Folder 513)
    - Hearne with dogs, 1990, undated (Box 40, Folder 514)
    - Forest, Bill, undated (Box 40, Folder 515)
    - Hollander, John, undated (Box 40, Folder 516)
    - Lerman, Colleen, 1972, 1976, undated (Box 40, Folder 517)
    - Unidentified individuals, undated (Box 40, Folder 518)
    - Dogs, 1991-1992, undated (Box 40, Folder 519)
    - Horses, undated (Box 40, Folder 520)
    - Photonegatives, miscellaneous, undated (Box 40, Folder 521)
      Vicki Hearne and Bandit
      Horses; road-side dinosaur attraction; museum
      Unidentified weddings
  - Audiotapes
    Conditions Governing Access
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - (A) "The Language and Music of the Wolves"; (B) "David and Banjo", 1989 January 1; 1; 01:12:13; There is static, clicks and pops on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 42, Item barcode 39002104611794)
    - "Scanlon bomb", 1992 February 6; 1; 00:29:52; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 42, Item barcode 39002104611802)
- Oversize, 1.25; (1 box)
  - From Series II. Advertisement for Adam's Task (Box 41, Folder 524)
  - From Series IV. Poster for Hearne poetry reading (Box 41, Folder 525)
  - From Series IV. Newspaper and magazine articles about Hearne (Box 41, Folder 526)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21; (1 box)
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 4 (Box 42, Folder 527)
  - Box 1, folder 6 (Box 42, Folder 528)
  - Box 1, folder 15 (Box 42, Folder 529)
  - Box 2, folder 17 (Box 42, Folder 530)
  - Box 2, folder 22 (Box 42, Folder 531)
  - Box 2, folder 25 (Box 42, Folder 532)
  - Box 3, folder 37 (Box 42, Folder 533)
  - Box 3, folder 39 (Box 42, Folder 534)
  - Box 4, folder 55 (Box 42, Folder 535)
  - Box 7, folder 100 (Box 42, Folder 536)
  - Box 8, folder 102 (Box 42, Folder 537)
  - Box 8, folder 107 (Box 42, Folder 538)
  - Box 8, folder 108 (Box 42, Folder 539)
  - Box 8, folder 109 (Box 42, Folder 540)
  - Box 11, folder 149 (Box 42, Folder 541)
  - Box 14, folder 183 (Box 42, Folder 542)
  - Box 15, folder 204 (Box 42, Folder 543)
  - Box 24, folder 348 (Box 42, Folder 544)
  - Box 25, folder 375 (Box 42, Folder 545)
  - Box 37, folder 495 (Box 42, Folder 546)
  - Box 39, folder 508 (Box 42, Folder 547)
  - Box 39, folder 508 (Box 42, Folder 548)
- Restricted Fragile Oversize, 1.42; (1 box)
  - Box 1, folder 7 (Box 43, Folder 551)
  - Box 1, folder 13 (Box 43, Folder 552)
  - Box 2, folder 17 (Box 43, Folder 553)
  - Box 2, folder 24 (Box 43, Folder 554)
  - Box 3, folder 32 (Box 43, Folder 555)
  - Box 7, folder 96 (Box 43, Folder 556)
  - Box 8, folder 102 (Box 43, Folder 557)
  - Box 11, folder 148 (Box 43, Folder 558)
  - Box 11, folder 149 (Box 43, Folder 559)
  - Box 14, folder 189 (Box 43, Folder 560)
  - Box 16, folder 229 (Box 43, Folder 561)
  - Box 18, folder 263 (Box 43, Folder 562)
  - Box 18, folder 264 (Box 43, Folder 563)
  - Box 18, folder 265 (Box 43, Folder 564)
  - Box 20, folder 301 (Box 43, Folder 565)
  - Box 39, folder 509 (Box 43, Folder 566)
  - Box 39, folder 510 (Box 43, Folder 567)
- Restricted Papers, 0.21; (1 box)
  Restricted until January 1, 2060. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - From Series I. Box 4, folder 48 (Box 44, Folder 568)
- 2008 Addition, 1983-2005; 1; (1 box)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  The 2008 Addition consists of material given by Vicki Hearne's brother, James Hearne, in 2008.
  The arrangement of the material corresponds with series headings in the main collection.
  - Correspondence
    - Incoming, 1983-1997, undated (Box 45, Folder 569-571)
    - Outgoing, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 572)
    - Third-party, 2001-04, undated (Box 45, Folder 573)
  - Writings
    - Books
      - Horse Breaking: the Obedience Method (with Bill Forest); typescript drafts and photographic proof sheets, undated (Box 45, Folder 574-577)
      - "The White Horse Murders" (with James Hearne); synopsis and typescript draft, undated (Box 45, Folder 578)
    - Articles
      - "Between the Poem and the Treatise," typscript draft, undated (Box 45, Folder 579)
      - "The Heart of an Aristocrat," typescript draft, undated (Box 45, Folder 580)
      - "How to Say 'Fetch!'," printed version, published in Raritan, 1983 Fall (Box 45, Folder 581)
      - "Something Funny About That Dog," typescript draft removed from spiral-bound notebook in folder 587, undated (Box 45, Folder 582)
      - "Tracking Dogs, Sensitive Horses, and the Traces of Speech," offprint originally published in Raritan, undated (Box 45, Folder 583)
    - Poetry
      - "Intermediate Philosophy," typescript draft, undated (Box 45, Folder 584)
      - Untitled poem, manuscript draft, written on cover of 1999 May 1 issue of Slate on Paper (Box 45, Folder 585)
      - Miscellaneous poems; manuscript and typed drafts, undated (Box 45, Folder 586)
    - Miscellaneous writings
      - Spiral-bound notebook containing various writings and drafts of letters, 2000 (Box 45, Folder 587)
      - Book proposals, undated (Box 45, Folder 588)
      - Miscellaneous notes, Internet site page printout, etc., 2005, undated (Box 45, Folder 589)
      - Poems by Neil Arditi and D.L. Garber, undated (Box 45, Folder 590)
    - Teaching files
      - Dog training class handouts, 2000, undated (Box 45, Folder 591)
      - Animal training and behavior articles, 1999-2000, undated (Box 45, Folder 592)
      - Yale University, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 593)
    - Articles about Hearne
      - Articles and book reviews, 1988-1998 (Box 45, Folder 594-595)
  - Photographs
    - Hearne and dogs, 1991, undated (Box 45, Folder 596)
    - Portfolio of photographs of limestone sculptures by Natalie Charkow, undated (Box 45, Folder 597)
    - Photonegatives, undated (Box 45, Folder 598-600)
  - Personal Files
    - "Runningmate" personal organizer containing address book, notes, business cards, etc., 1985-1992, undated (Box 45, Folder 601)